Uttam Jakku

Long Beach, CA | +1 5629392183 | uttamjakku96@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/uttam-jakku | github.com/StephenJakku

SUMMARY

Versatile developer with 3.4 years of experience in implementations of large-scale Middleware Applications and enablement of CI/CD automations using DevOps methodologies. Certified AWS Architect. In previous roles, slashed delivery times by 25% and ensured 98% on-time project completions. Currently pursuing my Masters in Computer Science at California State University, Long Beach. Looking for a challenging career opportunity which demands the best of my professional ability in terms of technical and managerial skills to bring further success to the organization, also enhancing my current skill set and knowledge base.

SKILLS

• DevOps • AWS • Jenkins • Git Sonatype Nexus • Mulesoft • API Jira • Python • C • Splunk Java • SOL • Service Now Ant Shell

EXPERIENCE

Accenture - Hyderabad, India

Application Development Analyst

Jun 2020 - Jul 2021

- Managed a team consisting of members ranging from Associate developers to Devops engineers in three locations (Hyderabad, Mumbai, Chennai) and collaborated with Business Partners, Operations, Stakeholders.
- Performed 300+ Mulesoft API/Application deployments to CloudHub and configuration management RAML deployment, Proxy deployments, Policies enforcements, Contracts, Gateway setup using Anypoint Platform.
- Developed a script for efficient management of users based on their active login sessions in Bitbucket leading to a saving of 50% of users licensing costs to the client.
- Proposed automated alerting system around the infrastructure to report frequently known issues as soon as they raise which resulted in quicker and more efficient fixes drastically reducing of the resolution times by 75%.
- Gained working knowledge of AWS Cloud environment and its tools and hands on knowledge of SSH, PGP and SFTP implementations for data security.

Accenture - Hyderabad, India

Application Development Associate

Mar 2018 - Jun 2020

- Been part of design, code, and support phases of implementing more than 250 integration solutions to meet business needs using IBM Integration Bus and its utilities.
- Implemented DevOps automations around Middleware architecture on a production scale using tools Jenkins, Bitbucket, Jira, Puppet, SonarQube and Sonatype Nexus tools resulting in savings of 50% deployment times and reduction of manual errors.
- Planned and executed user management schemes with the integration of Azure-AD, LDAP with Devops tools, Service Now, Jira and Deployment environments (Cloud and Local Servers), successfully managing around 200 users.
- Successfully migrated more than 2000 repositories from CVS to Bitbucket along with their 10 to 15 years of commit histories using shell scripting.
- Designed various strategies for automations and persuaded them by creating multiple CI/CD pipelines using Groovy, Ant and Shell scripts reducing manual efforts by more than 50%.

EDUCATION

California State University - Long Beach, CA

GPA: 4.0

Master of Science, Computer Science

Aug 2021 - May 2023 (Expected)

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University - Hyderabad, India

Sep 2013 - May 2017

Bachelor of Technology, Information Technology

AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS

Certifications & Training: Certified AWS Solutions Architect Associate and Splunk Fundamentals. MuleSoft Trained. **Awards:** "ACE – Accenture Celebrates Excellence" for the successful implementation of DevOps Infrastructure.